

David StotijnSenior Software Engineer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands • dstotijn@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/dstotijn • github.com/dstotijn

Career profile

Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years' experience building and maintaining distributed services on cloud infrastructure. Built a no-code product at a unicorn tech scale-up, used +1M/month by business customers for automating chat, email and voice workflows.

Designing and building (micro)services using **Go** and **TypeScript/JavaScript (Node.js)** on **AWS** and **Google Cloud Platform**. Working **full-stack**, combining backend and frontend using **React** and **Svelte**, interacting via **GraphQL** or **REST APIs**. Experienced as **tech lead** and **mentor**.

Work experience

Freelance Software Engineer, Self-employed at Hetty Software (2022—current)

Eventpartners

- Designed and built a modern stack (using **Node.js** and **React**) to support a multi-tenant
 SaaS platform for event software.
- NestJS (Node.js) Backend service ("modular monolith") with GraphQL server, guards and interceptors (using Rx.js), authentication and authorization, validation, various modules for business logic, Prisma for PostgreSQL based database storage.
 End-to-end testing using Jest. Deployed on Google Cloud Run.
- Next.js (React) Admin dashboard and customer facing content. Built custom components for event planning and registration form building. Used code generation for a type-safe GraphQL client.

Invopop Ltd.

- Built a low-code editor for reviewing and creating electronic invoice documents, using
 Svelte, Monaco Editor, WebAssembly and Web Workers.
- Helped refactor the admin dashboard to SvelteKit, using Tailwind UI components and connecting to the (Firestore based) database backend.

Framer, Full-stack Software Engineer (2019—2021)

 Designed, built and maintained web services (Go, Node.js) for team collaboration features such as commenting, access control, search and (image) asset management.

- Built software and infrastructure for Framer Sites, namely automated certificate management (using Let's Encrypt) and site hosting (using DynamoDB, S3, CloudFront, and other AWS services).
- Built a pipeline for automated screenshotting of Framer projects, for Dashboard and Open Graph usage (browser automation, image processing, storage).

MessageBird (2015—2019)

Engineering Manager (2019)

- Scaled up agile teams for New Product Development in a high growth environment, fostering autonomy and an ownership mentality.
- Wrote engineering guidelines and best practices for software design, high availability and infrastructure.
- Instrumental in executing the company's CPaaS strategy, empowering teams to build and maintain innovative new products and services in a highly available cloud infrastructure.

Tech Lead (2018—2019)

- Designed and built the (Go) backend of Flow Builder, a no-code product used +1M/month by business customers for automating SMS, Voice and Chat communications.
- Onboarded and coached software engineers to use Go as a primary language for backend service development.

Software Engineer (2015—2018)

 Built developer-friendly RESTful APIs (Go and PHP) on backend (micro)services/infrastructure for Chat and Voice products.

LimoenGroen, Drupal Developer (2014—2015)

 Built web applications using Drupal (PHP content management framework) for companies in energy, education, arts, nonprofit and government industries.

Constant IT, Technical Specialist (2008—2014)

- Full stack development of public websites, intranets and extranets. Specialized in tailor-made Drupal implementations.
- System administration of Linux web servers.

Side projects (open source)

Hetty, Author/maintainer (2020—present)

An HTTP toolkit for security research. It aims to become an open source alternative to commercial software like Burp Suite Pro, with powerful features tailored to the needs of the infosec and bug bounty community.

Education

Ba. Computer Science (1st year)

University of Amsterdam (2004—2005)

Propedeutics Computer Science

Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences (2003—2004)

Hobbies and Interests

- Music: playing piano and guitar, composition/production
- Running
- Programming and exploring tech in general
- Cooking and eating (emphasis on eating)